Guide to the Marshall T. Meyer Papers, 1902-2004 and undated, bulk 1984-1993 RL.00895
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Electronic Files Series, 1952-1995 and undated, Approximately 850 electronic files extracted from 32 floppy diskettes and 3 optical discs.
  Includes transcriptions written in English, Spanish, and Hebrew of documents authored by or related to Meyer, as well as an audio recording of Meyer speaking at the 1988 Eugen Rosenstock-Huessy Conference. Principally sermons given for the high holidays, files authored by Meyer also include prayers, memos, lectures, speeches, articles, columns, eulogies, letters to the editor, his 1952 Dartmouth thesis, correspondence, a summary and excerpts from a 1993 class entitled Jewish Responses to Death, and excerpts from the Confronting Injustice manuscript. This series also contains articles written about Meyer, transcriptions of published and unpublished interviews, speeches made at a conference about his work, and excerpts from other scholars' publications. RL00895-FL-018_Disk 018 contains the tape-counter numbers and summaries of some of the audio cassettes found in the Audiovisual Materials Series. Many of the files contain overlapping material and some are translations of work written in another language. Some files may be duplicates of documents included in the Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, and Teaching Material Series. Much of the contents of the floppy diskettes RL00895-FL-001 - RL00895-FL-020 are duplicated on RL00895-OP-001.Topics include religion, human rights, ethics, prejudice, personal words of condolence, and current events in Argentina, the U.S., and the Middle East. Arranged in original order as received.
  [Records have been migrated to a library server. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
  - MTM Book materials, 1952-1995 and undated, 25 folders, 108 files, 5.7 MB
    - Big Message
    - Community
    - Ecumenism
    - High Holidays
    - Latin America
    - Prayers
    - Prophets & Death
    - Social Action
    - Theology & Human Rights
    - Various
    - Rejects
  - Floppy disks, 1952-1995 and undated, 22 folders, 278 files, 11.6 MB
    - High Holidays
    - Uncategorized documents
  - Compact Discs, 1952-1995 and undated, 19 folders, 255 files, 388 MB
    - Big Message
    - Bits
    - Cuts
    - Death
    - Ecumenism
    - Espa&ntildeol
    - Heschel
    - High Holidays
    - Human Rights
    - Micro Tapes
    - New
    - Plavnick
    - Prayers
    - Prophets
    - Social Action
    - Theology
    - Transcriptions
    - 1988 Eugen Rosentock-Huessy Conference, Dartmouth College audio recording
- Oversize Material, 1944-1993 and undated, 5 boxes
  Consists of oversize files primarily from the Research Files Series. The bulk of the material comprises newspapers and clippings from or related to Argentina. Most of these chronicle the aftermath of the Dirty War/El Proceso. In addition to many clippings from Meyer's CONADEP files, articles on Madres de Plaza de Mayo, the trials of Argentina's military rulers in the mid-1980s, and the Catholic Church are included. While some clippings come from non-Argentine sources, most articles are published by domestic publications. In particular, a substantial collection of issues of the Jewish newspaper Nueva Presencia, dated between 1980 and 1987 can be found here. Issues of El Diario del Juicio from 1985 complete the newspapers. Additional material is comprised of photographs, degrees, and other awards given to Meyer. Materials are arranged in date order.
  - Research Files Series
    - Geographic Files (Argentina and Latin America)
      - El Diario del Juicio, 1985 (Argentina) (Box 83)
      - Nueva Presencia (Argentina), 1980, 1984, 1985 (Box 83)
      - Nueva Presencia, 1985-1986 Mar. (Box 84)
      - Nueva Presencia, 1986 Dec.-1987 Jan. (Box 85)
      - Various clippings from Argentina and Latin America, 1979-1992 and undated (Box 86)
      - Various clippings from Argentina and Latin America, 1971-1992 and undated (Box 87)
  - Personal Files Series
    - Photos, undated (Box 87)
    - Awards, honors, degrees, diplomas, 1944-1993 (Box 87)
    - Honors, awards, posters, 1984-1991 (Box 87)
- Accession (2011-0005), 1973-1996, 3 boxes
  - Articles about Meyer (Box 88)
  - Clippings, human rights 1983-1986 and undated (Box 88)
  - Condolences, 4 folders (Box 88)
  - Condolences, testimonials about Meyer (Box 88)
  - Correspondence (Box 88)
  - Diaspora Lives by Lionel Rolfe, circa 1994 (Box 88)
  - La Dimension Judia en la Represion Durante el Gobierno Militar en Argentina (1976-1983), 1985 (Box 88)
  - Homenaje a CONADEP, 1994 (Box 88)
  - Jewish Peace Lobby, 1989 (Box 88)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary Interns, 1985-1987 (Box 88)
  - Jfrej - Risk Taker Awards (Box 88)
  - Obituaries and Memoriams, 1993-1994, 5 folders (Box 88)
  - Obituaries and Memoriams, 1993-1994, Argentina, 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Obituaries, 1994, Israel (Box 88)
  - Research notes (Box 88)
  - Research notes, index cards (Box 89)
  - Sermon notes, 1992, undated (Box 89)
  - Subject files, Argentine (Box 89)
  - Tributes to Meyer (Box 89)
  - Vida Judaica en la Argentina (Box 89)
  - Writings by Meyer (Box 89)
  - You are my Witness, Reviews and Press (Box 89)
  - MTM - Argentine Jewry, 1979, VHS (Box 89)
  - 4 Disertaciones, Marshall T. Meyer, 1993 Aug., 2 copies on video optical disc, 3.14 GB (Box 89)
  - Marshall T. Meyer Tribute, Dario Ferguen, Adrian Gottfried, RA Mexico, Impacts of CJ on Latin America, 1996, Disk image derived from optical disc, 1 file, 796 MB (Box 89)
  - Celebracion 30 a&ntildeos del Seminario VHS audio, Disk images derived 3 optical discs containing audio recordings and an inventory, 8.9 GB (Box 89)
  - Mezvzot SRL, Graduacion F. Yafe, Disk image derived from optical disc, 4.3 GB (Box 89)
  - Oversized articles, obituaries, human rights (Box 90)
  - Inauguracion Bet El, Sabado y Domingo, 1973 June, audio tape reel (Box 90)